Ahmed Reda Said

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

I am a proactive Software Engineer with experience in Python and web development using React JS. I have handson experience in cloud computing, virtualization, and DevOps concepts, along with a solid foundation in data structures and algorithms. With problem-solving mindset, I have contributed to various projects and internships, showcasing my technical and collaborative abilities.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

A	Calandinatan	11 1 1	Callantian Ein	
Administrative	Co-ordinator.	Apousnaav	Collection Fii	m.

Aug 2023

Working with banks' files, attachments and emails. writing DCR excel sheets and coordinating with supervisors and collectors.

Maadi, Egypt

Software Engineering Internship, ALX Africa ☑

2022

Working on Sprints & developing C, Python, JavaScript and React programs.

Cairo, Egypt

Cloud Computing Internship, NTI □

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

Working on Cloud and Virtualization Concepts, Hypervisor, Data Center & The Virtual Data Center, and VMware Virtualization Solutions.

Online and In-Office, 6th of October, Giza

Web Development Internship, The Sparks Foundation ☑

2021 - 2022

Created and developed dynamic websites, worked on, Deployed, and maintained websites on AWS, perform testing methodologies and worked on C#, MySQL, Java.

Online

PROJECTS

Instagram Clone Project Using C# and MVC Design Pattern, Web Application

Using MVC and asp.net to implement methods of: user registration and authentication, post creation, profile management, search, follow and unfollow, likes and comments.

Voice Recognition Project Using TensorFlow, Pandas and NumPy, Desktop App

Using Python for Speech-to-Text Technology. I used MFCC algorithm to validate that system will whether recognize your voice depending on the accuracy of the algorithm applied or not.

Maze Solver Project Using Java and GUI, Desktop App

Using Java and Backtracking Algorithm. I implemented Depth-First, Breadth-First, and A-Star techniques.

Information Retrieval and Web Search Using Pandas and NumPy, Desktop App 2

Using Python for Data Retrieval and Processing. I used TF-IDF algorithm for tokenization and analysis.

Bus Saftey Data Warehouse, SSIS, Alteryx 🗷

Star schema app with fact table and 2 dimension tables describing the bus safety dataset.

Business Intelligence Analytical Report System Using Power BI, SSIS

Using SSIS i executed a MIS program to apply ETL on a real company dataset, and generate reports in Power BI.

Linux directories Controller Using C Language, Directory Manager Program

Using Virtual Box as a Virtual Machine - I implemented Linux file/directory methods: list, create, delete and rename.

Ahmed Reda Said

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming

Python, Java, C Linux, Virtualization, Hypervisor, AWS

Web Development

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React JS

Data Structure, Algorithms, Database, OOP, OS

Cloud Computing and DevOps

Computer Science

Version Control Technologies

Git and GitHub SQL Server, Power BI, Agile, UMLs

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Information System, Helwan University,

Sep 2019

Faculty of Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Z

Helwan, Egypt

Graduation project: ERP system - My role was to develop the CRM module ☑

GPA = 3.31 / 4

High School's Degree, Othman Ibn Affan

Graduated with an Excellent grade.

Sep 2016 – Jun 2019 15 May city, Egypt

CERTIFICATES

Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate - SFPC[™] □

Entry-level knowledge in Scrum.

WHM Administration Certification Exam (CWA) □

cPanel and WHM Proficiency

Huawei Certified ICT Associate (HCIA) ☑

Entry-level in Huawei certificates.

COURSES

Cloud and TCP/IP Pre-Requisite Knowledge, Dolfined

May 2022

Learned Networking basics, Terminologies and OSI model within layers.

Online

Cloud DevOps Engineer, Udacity ☐

May 2020 Online

Learned more about Infrastructure as Code (IAC), and CI/CD Pipelines.

May 2020

Deployed a static website page on AWS.

Online

LANGUAGES

Arabic

Cloud Developer, *Udacity* 🗗

English

German

Professional (B2)

Fundamental(A2)

SOFT SKILLS

Native

Familiar with Problem-Solving Process

The four basic Steps: defining the problem, brainstorming, picking the solution, and implementing the solution.

Innovation and Leadership

Good Communication and presentation skills

Public Speaking, Coordination and Team-work

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Military Status: Postponed

Ahmed Reda Said 2 / 2